AMGAD AHMED

Specialising in improving design maturity, strategy, and design systems.

🗓 +201113330337 🖂 ahamgad0@gmail.com 🔗 linkedin/in/ahamgad 合 amgad.figma.site

EXPERIENCE

Senior UX Designer

May 2024 - Present

Crowd Analyzer

- Develop innovative concepts for new products.
- A complete redesign for a wider customer base.
- Build design systems that align with emerging design trends.
- Market research and plan competitive analysis.

UI UX Lead

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

Penta-b

 Directed and assessed the design team's work to maintain high standards and optimize outcomes.

UI UX Lead

May 2023 - Oct 2023

Homzmart

- Building design system & design team.
- Product & UX strategy planning.
- Market research and plan competitive analysis. Conducted user research.
- Significantly improved user experience and branding consistency.

Design & Innovation Lead

Sep 2022 - May 2023

Talaat Moustafa Group (TMG)

- Product & UX strategy planning. Building design system & design team.
- Provided many product case studies.
- · Lead the design of the applications suite.
- Conducted user research and usability testing.

Senior UX Designer

Aug 2022 - Aug 2022

Nawy

Market research and plan competitive analysis. Perform user A/B testing.

Digital Product Designer

Jul 2017 - Aug 2022

G2K Group

- Lead the design of the applications suite.
- Created wireframes and motion prototypes for iteration. Conducted user research and usability testing.
- Shipped the redesign. Significantly improved user experience and branding consistency.

SUMMARY

A passionate, patient, and pragmatic design leader specialising in design systems, with 9 years of experience. Vast knowledge of improving design maturity, product design processes, and methodologies, including design sprint facilitation. Consulted on, created, and maintained first or early design systems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Architecture - BArch, Fine Arts.

2009 - 2016

COURSES

UX Management

Interaction Design Foundation

UX Research & Design

University of Michigan

Google UX Design

Google

SKILLS

Management / Leadership / Design Systems / Research / Usability Testing / Visual Design / Strategic Planning / Team Building / Web Design / Mobile App Design / Workshop Facilitation / Branding / Packaging / Illustration